# Huda Abdul Rahman Al-Fajri

## PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Nationality: Saudi

Mobile No.: 0505466886

E-MAIL: houda.a.al@hotmail.com

## **OBJECTIVE:**

Self-motivated professional with 5 years of experience as Human Resource Manager; I am looking for a professional human resource position, coming with extensive knowledge of human resource principles and ability to handle complex problems using outstanding organizational and time management skills.

#### **EDUCATION:**

"[MBA / Dissertation in Management]"
"[Ahlia University / Kingdom of Bahrain]"

"[2012]" "[Diploma / Human Resource Management]"

"[Oxford Training College / Kingdom of British]"

"[2010]" "[Bachelor / Social sciences]"

"[King Faisal University/ Kingdom of Saudi Arabia]"

## COURSES:

Principles and Basics of Insurance Certificate "[2012]"
 Impact Training and Consulting Center

• Insurance Foundation Certificate (IFCE) "[2011-2012]"
The Institute of Banking (SAMA)

Mastering English language Skills and Conversation "[2011-2012]"
 Berlitz Institute of Languages

Marketing skills and sales management "[2011]"
 Dhahran International Exhibitions Company

Customer Service, Data entry, Management contracts
 Unity Centre for Women in Business (Chamber of Commerce)

"[2009/2010]"

Managing Business Pressure
 Program Prince Mohammed Bin Fahd Program

"[2009/2010]"

• English Course Canadian Language Center "[2009/2010]"

 Computer & Secretarial Certificate Alhussan Training Center "[2004/2005]"

# Skills:

Languages: Arabic: Mother Tongue

English: Very Good (reading-writing-speaking)

<u>Computer</u>: JD Edwards Software (HR Management)
Good Microsoft Office

## **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

"[Years 2014 –2021]" "[**HR Manager**]" "[Alfares Holding Company]"

"[Al-khobar, Saudi Arabia]"

#### <u>Job Responsibilities</u>:

- Maintains the work structure by updating job requirements and job descriptions for all positions.
- Maintains organization staff by establishing a recruiting, testing, and interviewing program; counseling managers on candidate selection; conducting and analyzing exit interviews; recommending changes.
- Prepares employees for assignments by establishing and conducting orientation and training programs.
- Maintains a pay plan by conducting periodic pay surveys; scheduling and conducting job
  evaluations; preparing pay budgets; monitoring and scheduling individual pay actions;
  recommending, planning, and implementing pay structure revisions.

- Ensures planning, monitoring, and appraisal of employee work results by training managers to coach and discipline employees; scheduling management conferences with employees; hearing and resolving employee grievances; counseling employees and supervisors.
- Maintains employee benefits programs and informs employees of benefits by studying and
  assessing benefit needs and trends; recommending benefit programs to management;
  directing the processing of benefit claims; obtaining and evaluating benefit contract bids;
  awarding benefit contracts; designing and conducting educational programs on benefit
  programs.
- Ensures legal compliance by monitoring and implementing applicable human resource government requirements; conducting investigations; maintaining records;
- Maintains management guidelines by preparing, updating, and recommending human resource policies and procedures.
- Maintains historical human resource records by designing a filing and retrieval system; keeping past and current records.
- Maintains professional and technical knowledge by attending educational workshops; reviewing professional publications; establishing personal networks; participating in professional societies.
- Completes human resource operational requirements by scheduling and assigning employees; following up on work results.
- Prepares employee separation notices and related documentation, and conducts exit interviews to determine reasons behind separations.
- Maintains human resource staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training employees.
- Contributes to team effort by accomplishing related results as needed

```
"[Years 2011 – 2013]"
"[HR Specialist]"
```

"[Al Sagr Insurance Company]"
"[Al-khobar, Saudi Arabia]"

#### <u>Iob Responsibilities</u>:

- Preparing and reviewing compensation and benefits packages
- Administering health and life insurance programs
- Preparing or updating employment records related to hiring, transferring, promoting, and terminating

- Maintain organizational charts and detailed job descriptions along with salary records
- Overseeing hiring process, which includes coordinating job posts, reviewing resumes, and performing reference checks
  - Implementing the organization's recruiting strategy
  - Interviewing applicants
  - Administering pre-employment tests
  - Assisting with completing background investigations
  - Processing transfers, promotions, and terminations
- Informing job applicants of job duties, responsibilities, benefits, schedules, working conditions, promotion opportunities, etc.
- Ensuring new hire paperwork is completed and processed
- Explaining human resources policies, procedures, laws, and standards to new and existing employees
- Addressing any employment relations issues, such as work complaints and harassment allegations
- Processing all personnel action forms and ensuring proper approval
- Process employees' queries and respond in a timely manner
- Stay up-to-date and comply with changes in labor legislation
- Develop and implement HR policies throughout the organization

<sup>\*\*</sup> References are available on request